Guide to the Civil War Stereographs 1861-1865 PR 65-1
New-York Historical Society
- Ruins of North Eastern Depot, blown up during the evacuation of Charleston (about 300 lives lost.), 1865 (Item 796-22)
  Ruins of North Eastern Depot, blown up during the Confederate evacuation of Charleston.
- Meeting Street, ruins of Secession Hall and Circular Church, with St. Phillips in distance., 1865 (Item 796-23)
  Meeting Street, ruins of Secession Hall and Circular Church, with St. Phillips in distance.
- Meeting Street, ruins of Secession Hall and Circular Church, with St. Phillips in distance., 1865 (Item 796-24)
  Meeting Street, ruins of Secession Hall and Circular Church (with scaffolding), with St. Phillips in distance.
- Looking down Meeting Street-Ruins of theatre and Circular Church, with Mills House and St. Michael's in the distance., 1865 (Item 796-25)
  Looking down Meeting Street with ruins of theatre and Circular Church (with scaffolding), with Mills House and St. Michael's in the distance.
- Looking down Meeting Street-Ruins of theatre and Circular Church, with Mills House and St. Michael's in the distance., 1865 (Item 796-26)
- Looking down Meeting Street-Ruins of theatre and Circular Church, with Mills House and St. Michael's in the distance., 1865 (Item 796-27)
- Tomb in rear of Circular Church, showing the effect of shell., 1865 (Item 796-28)
  Destroyed tomb behind Circular Church.
- O'Conner House, where Union Officers were confined under fire., 1865 (Item 796-29)
  O'Conner House, where Union Officers were confined under fire.
- Mills House., 1865 (Item 796-30)
  Two men in foreground with the Mills House in the background.
- East Battery, looking South., 1865 (Item 796-31)
  East Battery, looking South, gutted house, right.
- East Battery, looking North, ruins of Blakely gun in foreground., 1865 (Item 796-32)
  East Battery, looking North, ruins of Blakely gun in foreground.
- Club house at the race course., 1865 (Item 796-33)
  Club house at the race course.
- Tomb of J. C. Calhoun., 1865 (Item 796-34)
  Tomb of John C. Calhoun.
- Ruins of Secession Hall, Charleston, S. C., ca. 1861, published later (Item 796-35)
  Ruins of Secession Hall, Charleston, S. C.
- Ruins of Secession Hall, Charleston, S. C., ca. 1861, published later (Item 796-36)
- Ruins of Secession Hall, Charleston, S. C., 1863, published later (Item 796-37)
- Charleston, S.C., O'Connor House where Union officers were confined under fire (Item 796-38)
  Men sitting among rubble of a home, while O'Connor house stands untouched.
- View from the parapet of Fort Moultrie, Charleston Harbor, S. C., looking N.E., 1865 (Item 797-1)
  View from the parapet of Fort Moultrie, S.C., with cannon in foreground and flag in background.
- Interior view of Fort Moultrie, Charleston Harbor, S. C., looking through the sallyport., ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 797-2)
  Interior view of Fort Moultrie, Charleston Harbor, S. C., building in the center, stacks of cannonballs.
- Interior view of Ft. Moultrie, S. C., ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 797-3)
  Interior view of Ft. Moultrie, S. C., showing shacks and earthen fortifications.
- Beach view of Sullivan's Island from Fort Moultrie, Charleston, S. C., ca. 1867 (Item 797-4)
  View from Fort Moultrie of the beach, palmettos and a house, artillery in the foreground.
- Interior view of Fort Moultrie, Charleston, S. C., 1867 (Item 797-5)
  Stacks of cannonballs, and fortifications, interior of Fort Moultrie, South Carolina.
- Interior of Fort Moultrie, Sullivans Island., 1865 (Item 797-6)
  Interior of Fort Moultrie, Sullivans Island looking toward sallyport and the water.
- Interior of Fort Moultrie, Moultrieville in the distance., 1865 (Item 797-7)
  Interior of Fort Moultrie, fortifications in ruins, homes of Moultrieville in the distance.
- Sally-Port of Fort Moultrie., 1865 (Item 797-8)
  Sally-Port of Fort Moultrie with a soldier standing in front.
- Union flag raising April 12, 1865, Fort Sumter on the Charleston side. (Item 798-1)
  Flag on parapet of Fort Sumter, with steamboats beyond.
- Interior view of Fort Sumter, ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 798-2)
  View of Fort Sumter showing breach in fortifications.
- Fort Sumter, ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 798-3)
  Damaged masonry fortifications of Fort Sumter, light house structure in background.
- Fort Sumter, ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 798-4)
  Interior view of Fort Sumter.
- Exterior view of Fort Sumter, Charleston Harbor, S. C., ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 798-5)
  Exterior ruin of Fort Sumter with lighthouse, Charleston Harbor, S. C.
- South-West view of Fort Sumter, Charleston Harbor, S. C., ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 798-6)
  Men on beach in front of Fort Sumter, lighthouse above.
- View of Fort Sumpter [sic.] Interior, showing remains of a casemate and other ruins., ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 798-7)
  View of Fort Sumter's interior showing remains of a casemate and other ruins.
- The sea face of Fort Sumpter [sic], Charleston Harbor, S.C., looking towards Morris Island, showing the debris, shot and shell., ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 798-8)
  Destroyed section of Fort Sumter.
- Interior of Fort Sumpter [sic], Charleston Harbor, S. C., April 14, 1865, pending the ceremony of raising the old Flag. (Item 798-9)
  Crowd of people gathered for the flag ceremony at Fort Sumter.
- Interior of Fort Sumpter [sic], Charleston Harbor, S. C., April 14, 1865, pending the ceremony of raising the old Flag. (Item 798-10)
- Interior of Fort Sumpter [sic], Charleston Harbor, S. C., April 14, 1865, pending the ceremony of raising the old Flag. (Item 798-11)
- Interior of Fort Sumpter [sic], Charleston Harbor, S. C., April 14, 1865, pending the ceremony of raising the old Flag. (Item 798-12)
- View from the parapet of Ft. Sumpter [sic], S. C. on the day of the raising of the old flag., 1865 (Item 798-13)
- Fort Sumter-after the first bombardment in 1861. (Item 798-14)
  Fort Sumter-after the first bombardment in 1861.
- Fort Sumter in April 1861 after Anderson evacuated. (Item 798-15)
  Soldiers in interior of fort, with the Stars and Bars of the Confederacy flying above.
- Fort Sumter, Charleston Harbor., ca. 1865 (Item 798-16)
  Boat with Fort Sumter in the background.
- N.E. Angle, Fort Sumter, 1863 (Item 798-17)
  Interior view of Fort Sumter, showing destruction and rubble after Union bombardment.
- Fort Sumter on its evacuation (by Rebels) Feb. 18, 1865 when taken by the Federal forces. (Item 798-18)
- Fort Sumter, 1861. (Item 798-19)
  View of Fort Sumter.
- Interior of Fort Sumter, April 14,1861. (Item 798-20)
  Cannons and rubble in the interior of Fort Sumter, 1861.
- Interior view of Fort Sumter, showing the Northeast angle, Charleston, S. C., ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 798-21)
  Interior view of Fort Sumter, with General Hampton and Bishop Lynch standing next to Columbiad gun.
- Fort Sumter after evacuation, flagpole shot away twice., 1861 (Item 798-22)
  Interior view of Fort Sumter, with flagpole, center, destroyed walls in background.
- Fort Sumpter [sic] from the bar., 1865 (Item 798-23)
  Men seated on the beach with Fort Sumter in the background.
- Palmetto fortifications on the channel side of Fort Sumpter [sic.], 1865 (Item 798-24)
  Fortifications made of palmetto logs on the channel side of Fort Sumter.
- Interior of Fort Sumpter [sic] showing gabions and bomb proofs., 1865 (Item 798-25)
  Interior of Fort Sumter showing gabions supporting ramp to parapets, and bombproof shelters.
- Interior of Fort Sumpter [sic] looking toward Charleston., 1865 (Item 798-26)
  Interior of Fort Sumter looking toward Charleston, with men and camera at left.
- Interior of Fort Sumpter [sic] looking toward Charleston., 1865 (Item 798-27)
  Interior of Fort Sumter looking toward Charleston, with baskets used for gabions in foreground.
- Interior of Fort Sumpter [sic] looking toward Charleston., 1865 (Item 798-28)
- Interior of Fort Sumpter [sic], James Island in the distance., 1865 (Item 798-29)
  Interior of Fort Sumter, with rows of gabions supporting structure of the fort.
- North wall of Fort Sumpter [sic.], 1865 (Item 798-30)
  Brick wall of Fort Sumter with cannon on top.
- A parapet of Fort Sumpter [sic], looking toward Morris Island., 1865 (Item 798-31)
  A parapet of Fort Sumter with cannons.
- Interior of Fort Sumpter [sic], looking toward Morris Island., 1865 (Item 798-32)
  Interior of Fort Sumter looking toward Morris Island, gabions supporting parapet.
- Interior of Fort Sumpter [sic], looking toward Morris Island, Charlest'n, S. C., 1865 (Item 798-33)
- Interior of Fort Sumpter [sic], showing light house., 1865 (Item 798-34)
  Interior of Fort Sumter with lighthouse.
- Sea face of Fort Sumpter [sic], looking toward Morris Island., 1865 (Item 798-35)
  Fort Sumter coast littered with war debris and men surveying the scene.
- Sea face of Fort Sumpter [sic], shewing [sic] broken guns, shot, shell, &c., 1865 (Item 798-36)
  Man (John P. Soule?) sitting next to cannon that has tumbled down from Fort Sumter.
- Sea face of Fort Sumpter [sic], shewing [sic] broken guns, shot, shell, &c., 1865 (Item 798-37)
- Sea face of Fort Sumpter [sic], shewing [sic] broken guns, & c., 1865 (Item 798-38)
  Cannon and row of timbers in the rubble below Fort Sumter.
- Sea face of Fort Sumpter [sic.], 1865 (Item 798-39)
  Sea face of Fort Sumter with war debris including shells on the shore.
- Sea face of Fort Sumpter [sic], shewing [sic] light house, broken guns, & c., 1865 (Item 798-40)
  Sea face of Fort Sumter, showing light house, broken guns, and other debris.
- Fort Johnson, James Island, Fort Sumter in the distance, 1865 (Item 798-41)
  Fort Johnson, James Island, with cannons lining the parapet, Fort Sumter in the distance.
- Fort Sumter after the bombardment., ca.1861-ca.1865, published later (Item 798-42)
  Fort Sumter after the bombardment, cannon and timbers lining the shore.
- Raising the old flag over Fort Sumter., 1865, published later (Item 798-43)
  Crowd of people enjoying the flag ceremony at Fort Sumter.
- Photographic war history. The war for the Union., 1865, published later (Item 798-44)
- View from an elevation in front of the Capitol, Nashville, Tenn., ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 799-1)
  Houses and sheds in front of the Capitol building Nashville, Tenn.
- View from the front of the State House looking over the field during the battle of Nashville, Tenn., Dec. 15th and 16th, 1864. (Item 799-2)
  Men and women looking toward the battle from in front of the State House.
- View from the front of the State House looking over the field during the battle of Nashville, Tenn., Dec. 15th and 16th, 1864. (Item 799-3)
- View from the front of the State House, Nashville, Tenn., during the battle of Dec. 14, 1864. Showing in the distance the Federal camps, in the foreground soldiers and civilians watching the fight. (Item 799-4)
  View from the front of the State House, Nashville, Tenn., during the battle of Dec. 14, 1864, with soldiers and civilians in the foreground watching the fight.
- Bridge over the Cumberland River on the Louisville and Nashville R. R., 1864 (Item 799-5)
  Men standing on bridge with guardhouses over the Cumberland River on the Louisville and Nashville R. R.
- The fortified bridge over the Cumberland River on the Louisville and Nashville R. R., ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 799-6)
  Boy on horse below the fortified bridge over the Cumberland River on the Louisville and Nashville R. R.
- Knoxville R. R. depot at Chattanooga. Group of Rebel prisoners waiting transporta. North., ca.1864 (Item 799-7)
  Knoxville Railroad depot at Chattanooga, group of Confederate prisoners waiting transportation North.
- View on the top of Lookout Mountain, Tenn., ca.1864 (Item 799-8)
  Man climbing ladders leading up the side of Lookout Mountain, Tennessee.
- Umbrella Rock, Lookout Mountain, Tenn., ca. 1864 (Item 799-9)
  Two men seated underneath a rock formation.
- Pulpit Rock, Lookout Mountain, Tenn., the place where Jeff. Davis addressed the rebel armies., ca.1863 (Item 799-10)
  Men seated on Pulpit Rock, Lookout Mountain.
- View from the Heights opposite Knoxville, Tenn., ca.1864 (Item 799-11)
  Tents located on mountain with a view Knoxville across the river.
- Federal camp at Johnsonville, Tenn., ca.1864, published later (Item 799-12)
  Troops of the 1st Tennessee Colored Battery near depot platform before evacuation from Johnsonville.
- Railroad depot at Nashville, Tenn., ca.1864, published later (Item 799-13)
  Railroad depot at Nashville, Tenn. with locomotives lined up along side it.
- Chattanooga, Tenn., ca.1861-ca.1865, published later (Item 799-14)
  Confederate prisoners waiting outside the railroad depot to be transported north.
- Lulu Lake on Lookout Mountain., ca.1861-ca.1865, published later (Item 799-15)
  Lulu Lake on Lookout Mountain.
- Firing the gun with shrapnel at a target a mile distant in the Potomac., ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 800-1)
  Man pointing into the distance near soldiers and a cannon on the banks of the Potomac.
- Army of the Potomac encampment of St. Peter's Church, Virginia., ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 800-2)
  Officers standing in a field with tents in the background.
- Magazine, Ft. Brady, Va., ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 800-3)
  Soldiers standing outside a magazine at Fort Brady, Va.
- Loading a big gun, Fort Corcoran, Va., ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 800-4)
  Soldiers loading a large gun at Fort Corcoran, Va.
- Interior of Ft. Totten, Va., ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 800-5)
  Soldiers at Fort Totten [Washington, D.C.?] with artillery.
- Interior of fortifications, near Ft. Brady Va. Block houses., ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 800-6)
  Log block houses near Fort Brady, Va.
- Falls Church, Va., ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 800-7)
  Large brick house behind a wooden fence.
- Lieut. Gen. Grant and chief of staff, Gen. Rawlins, at his head quarters, at Cold Harbor, Va. Taken June, 14th 1864. (Item 800-8)
  Lieut. Gen. Grant looking at map or other document, with chief of staff, General Rawlins, at his headquarters, at Cold Harbor, Va.
- Signal corps, Cobb's Hill., ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 800-9)
  Signal corps standing in front of log structure.
- Colored pickets on duty near Dutch Gap., ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 800-10)
  African American pickets on duty near Dutch Gap shown taking aim with rifles.
- Gen. Butler's [headquarters near Varina, Va.], ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 800-11)
  House with log sheds attached and with soldiers outside.
- Colored Army teamsters, Cobb Hill, Va., ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 800-12)
  Seven African-American Army teamsters standing in front of wooden shed and wagon.
- Quarters 10th Regt. U.S. Colored Troops, Va. Ft. Brady in the distance., ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 800-13)
  Soldiers standing outside of the tents of the 10th Regiment U.S. Colored Troops, Va.
- Main battery, Ft. Brady, Va., ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 800-14)
  Soldiers standing next to a large piece of artillery.
- Interior of the Union fort Sedgwick, called by the rebel soldiers "Fort Hell," showing Union soldiers on the breastworks,. This view was taken the Morning after the storming of Petersburg, Va., April 2d, 1865 (Item 800-15)
  Soldiers standing on breastworks made of logs filled with earth.
- Ditch and "Cheavaux de Frise" in front of the Union Fort Sedgwick, called by the Rebel soldiers "Fort Hell." This view was taken the morning after the storming of Petersburgh, Va., April 2d, 1865. (Item 800-16)
  Ditch and cheavaux-de-frise in front of the Union Fort Sedgwick.
- Falls Church., 1862 (Item 800-17)
  House with wooden fence around it.
- Hotel at Sulphur Springs, Va. North view., 1862 (Item 800-18)
  Wagon in foreground on street in front of hotel at Sulphur Springs, Virginia
- U.S. Soldiers graves at 2nd Corps hospital, Carpenters farm, one mile south of Wilderness Church., ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 800-19)
  Man standing looking over graves with headstones.
- Cumberland Landing, ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 800-20)
  Two men in the foreground looking over a map with tents and horses in the background.
- View of carpenter, wheelwright, and harness shops at headquarters Army of the Potomac, April, 1864. (Item 800-21)
  Shop tents at the headquarters Army of the Potomac.
- Capt. H. Smith's mess, Co. D, 93 N. Y. V., Bealton, Va. August, 1863 (Item 800-22)
  Capt. H. Smith's and another officers of Co. D, 93 N. Y. V., being served a meal by African Americans at Bealton, Va.
- Residence John Minor Botts, Va., southeast, September, 1863. (Item 800-23)
  Soldiers in front of the John Minor Botts residence, men and women on the porch.
- Removing the wounded across the Rappahannock, under a Flag of Truce, after the Battle of Chancellorsville., May 1863 (Item 800-24)
  Town on the banks of the Rappahannock, group of soldiers waiting to cross.
- Stone church, Centreville, used as a hospital, after the battle of the 18th July, 1861. (Item 800-25)
  Stone church, Centreville, used as a hospital, after the first battle of Bull Run, July 18, 1861, with picket on duty in the foreground.
- Quaker guns, Centreville., ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 800-26)
  Man pretending to light the fuse of a log made to look like a cannon.
- Winter quarters, Confederate army, Centreville, south view, March 1862. (Item 800-27)
  Roof tops of log cabins.
- Winter quarters, Confederate army, Manassas, Va., south view, March 1862. (Item 800-28)
  Log cabins of the Confederate army.
- Principal fort at Centreville, 1862 (Item 800-29)
  Two men (one possibly the photographer, Barnard) standing within a rough fortress.
- Fort on heights of Centreville, mounting Quaker guns, March, 1862. (Item 800-30)
  Soldiers and Quaker guns on the heights of Centreville.
- Building railroad bridge, across Cedar Run near Catlett's Station. Destroyed by the Confederates when they fell back before the Army of the Potomac, under Gen'l Meade, Oct. 13, 1863. (Item 800-31)
  Re-building railroad bridge, across the Cedar Run near Catlett's Station after it had been destroyed by the Confederates when they fell back before the Army of the Potomac, under Gen'l Meade, Oct. 13, 1863.
- White House, formerly residence of Mrs. Custis Washington. Now the residence of Col. Lee, May 17, 1862. Since burned. (Item 800-32)
  White House, once owned by Martha Custis Washington, later by W.H.F. Lee, May 17, 1862, later burned down.
- Bridge over the north fork of the Rappahannock, near Sulphur Springs, Va., 1862 (Item 800-33)
  People walking over a bridge constructed of logs and planks.
- Erecting bridge across north fork of Rappahannock, near Sulphur Springs, Va., 1862 (Item 800-34)
  Erecting bridge across north fork of Rappahannock, near Sulphur Springs, Va.
- Rappahannock bridge. South view., 1862 (Item 800-35)
  Rappahannock bridge, man on plank walkway on the outside of the bridge, animals and wagons crossing main part.
- Fugitive Negroes fording the Rappahannock, fleeing from Jackson's army., 1862 (Item 800-36)
  Rappahannock River, Va. Fugitive African Americans fording the Rappahannock.
- Railroad depot and yard, Culpepper [sic]., 1862 (Item 800-37)
  Railroad depot with wagons in the yard, Culpeper, Virginia.
- Street approaching Warrenton. Court house in the distance., 1862 (Item 800-38)
  Street approaching Warrenton, with the courthouse in the distance.
- Court house in Warrenton., 1862 (Item 800-39)
  Courthouse in Warrenton, Virginia.
- View in Warrenton., 1862 (Item 800-40)
  View in on a street in Warrenton, Virginia.
- Hotel at Sulphur Springs, Virginia. Rear view., 1862 (Item 800-41)
  Rear view of hotel at Sulphur Springs, Virginia, tents pitched on the lawn.
- Hotel at Warrenton Springs, Va. Street view south., 1862 (Item 800-42)
  Hotel at Warrenton Springs, Va., looking south down the street.
- Catlett's Station., 1862 (Item 800-43)
  Soldiers on top of railroad cars on siding by Catlett's Station.
- Aquia Creek Landing, February, 1863. (Item 800-44)
  Aquia Creek Landing with steamboats and sailing vessels in the water beyond the town.
- Embarkation of the Ninth Army Corps at Aquia Creek Landing, February, 1863. (Item 800-45)
  Soldiers leaving for the war at Aquia Creek Landing.
- View at Aquia Creek Landing, from Commissary Department., 1863 (Item 800-46)
  View at Aquia Creek Landing from Commissary Department showing docks, railroad tracks and moored steamboat.
- Lacy House, Falmouth, Va. View from the south, March, 1863. (Item 800-47)
  View from the south of the Lacy House, Falmouth, Virginia., with wagons out front.
- Ruins of bridge at Germania Ford, where the troops crossed at under Gen'l Grant, May 4,1864. (Item 800-48)
  Ruins of bridge at Germania Ford, where the Union troops under Grant crossed, May 4,1864.
- Ruins of bridge at Germania Ford, where the troops crossed at under Gen'l Grant, May 4,1864. (Item 800-49)
  Ruins of bridge at Germania Ford, where the troops crossed at under Gen'l Grant, May 4,1864.
- Departed greatness, a relic of the past century, found near Guiness' Station, Va., May 21, 1864. (Item 800-50)
  18th century carriage with tattered canopy found near Guiness Station, Virginia.
- Bethel Church, Va., headquarters Gen. Burnside, May 23, 1864. (Item 800-51)
  Bethel Church, Virginia., headquarters of General Burnside, May 23, 1864.
- Canvas pontoon bridges at Hanovertown Ferry on the Pamunky [sic], constructed by the 50th N. Y. V. Engineers, May 28, 1864. (Item 800-52)
  Canvas pontoon bridges at Hanovertown Ferry on the Pamunkey River, constructed by the 50th N. Y. V. Engineers, May 28, 1864.
- Pontoon bridges at Hanovertown Ferry on the Pamunky [sic], constructed by the 50th N. Y. V. Engineers, May 28, 1864. (Item 800-53)
  Wagons crossing pontoon bridges at Hanovertown Ferry on the Pamunkey River, constructed by the 50th N. Y. V. Engineers, May 28, 1864.
- Ruins of bridge at Mrs. Nelson's crossing on the Pamunky [sic], 28th May, 1864. (Item 800-54)
  Soldiers setting up pontoon bridge next to the ruins of another bridge.
- Old Church Hotel, Va., June 2nd, 1864. (Item 800-55)
  Old Church Hotel with horses tied up in front.
- View on Battle-field of Cold Harbor., 1865 (Item 800-56)
  Human remains on the Cold Harbor battlefield.
- Savage Station, Va., June 27,1862., 1862, published later (Item 800-57)
  Covered wagons and horses with train cars in the distance.
- A field hospital scene., 1862, published later (Item 800-59)
  Wounded soldiers lying on the ground underneath a tree.
- Savage Station, Va., June 27,1862., 1862, published later (Item 800-59)
- Troops crossing the Rappahannock river on a pontoon bridge., 1864, published later (Item 800-60)
  Troops and wagons crossing the Rappahannock River on a pontoon bridge.
- Unburied dead on battlefield., ca.1862, published later (Item 800-61)
  Unburied dead at Gaines' Mills, Virginia.
- Unburied dead on battlefield., ca. 1862, published later (Item 800-62)
  Unburied dead in the woods at Gaines' Mills, Virginia.
- Unburied dead on battlefield., ca. 1862, published later (Item 800-63)
- Collecting remains of the dead., ca.1861-ca.1865, published later (Item 800-64)
  Collection of dead Union soldiers that were buried on the battlefield in unmarked graves.
- Collecting remains of the dead., ca.1861-ca.1865, published later (Item 800-65)
- Collecting remains of the dead., ca.1861-ca.1865, published later (Item 800-66)
- The Ambulance corps, ca. 1861-ca. 1865, published later (Item 800-67)
  Soldiers carrying wounded and dead on stretchers, and loading them aboard an ambulance.
- Interior of Fort Sedgwick., ca.1861-ca.1865, published later (Item 800-68)
  Interior of Fort Sedgwick.
- Encampment at Cumberland Landing, Va., ca.1862, published later (Item 800-69)
  Soldiers seated on hill above camp at Cumberland Landing, Virginia., on the Pamunkey River in May 1862.
- Evacuation of Port Royal, Va., May 30, 1864., 1864, published later (Item 800-70)
  Soldiers boarding steamboats from wharf made of pontoons, Port Royal, Virginia.
- A group of "contrabands", ca.1861-ca.1865, published later (Item 800-71)